Yetemegn Lemma

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer skilled in React, Redux, Javascript, and RoR with experience developing responsive desktop and mobile applications and working with clients. I am motivated and intrigued by pair programming because I think collaboration is essential to bringing original ideas to life. I co-founded a startup with the greatest team possible that develops the best technology and offers the best client solutions.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, React Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, SQL, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Postman, Figma, Chrome

Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Leadership,

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

August, 2022 - Present

HandyMate App — HandyMate is a website where users can book a service, cancel a booking. The user can also see the details of a service, ratings of the service.

• Built with: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, Javascript, Bootstrap - (Live Demo | Project Repository)

Bookstore — Responsive website to view book logs and help users manage their book logs

Built with: Javascript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3 - (<u>Live Demo</u> | <u>Project Repository</u>)

Math Magicians — Math Magicians is a website for math fans to do mathematical calculations and read fun, useful math quotes.

• Built with: Javascript, HTML5, CSS3 - (Live Demo | Project Repository)

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

September, 2022 - May, 2023

- Mentored junior web developers by offering technical assistance through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Managed to give guidance and suggestions for sustaining motivation to ensure longevity in the program.

Achibba Solutions Startup Technology

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Co-Founder/ Team Leader

August, 2021 – July, 2022

- Co-founded the startup Achibba Solutions, which developes cutting-edge technology with an emphasis on meeting all user requirements as they arise.
- Created significant links with troubled consumers using communication, empathy, and crisis management skills, which raised customer satisfaction and enhanced marketing.
- Due to my thorough, client-focused approach to sales and service, I consistently received exceptional monthly reviews from customers.

Hiveworks Trading PLC.

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Tech Support Specialist

January, 2020 - August, 2021

• Designed a report format for dispatch and sales, improved the company's sales by 5% in less than a month.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE August, 2022 – Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Developed projects using Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux while simultaneously spending more than 1300 hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack programming.
- Developed expertise in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

HiLCoE School of Computer Science and Technology **Degree, Computer Science**

September, 2016 - October, 2019

- Relevant coursework Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Al, Xamarine, PHP.
- Built an Attendance Management System with Fingerprint Biometric authentication as a final project.